Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.thirt Mss.B.B61.inventory13
American Philosophical Society
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents T
  - Tozzer, Alfred M. (Box 90-91)
    - To Boas, 1936 June 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Mar. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 May 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec. 13; 1p
    - Found at end of Dec. 1939, 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Oct. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Dec. 25; 2p
    - From Bryan, R.W., 1931 Apr. 28
    - From Downes, M., 1916 June 12
    - From Kroeber, A.L., 1917 Jan. 16
    - From Mechling, W.H., 1913 Nov. 10
    - From Parrott, F.
    - See carbon copy, 1929 Jan. 28
    - From Pruneda, A., 1914 Jan. 23
    - From Pruneda, A., 1914 May 23
    - From Pruneda, A., 1914 Nov. 9
    - From Whorf, B.L., 1930 Oct. 1
    - To Sophie Boas, 1912 May 1
    - To Sophie Boas, 1912 May 1
    - To Fletcher, 1911 May 8
    - To Keppel, F.F., 1933 Mar. 21; 1p
    - Enc. with Tozzer, A.M., 1933 Mar. 21
  - Trachtenberg, Dusja (Box 91)
    - See Boas, F. (to Open letter), 1940 Dec. 23
    - From Burke, B.S., 1941 Jan. 9
    - Found at end of Dec. 1940, 1p
    - From Lee, Josephine, 1940 Jan. 30
  - Traeger, P. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Sep. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 16; 1p
  - Trager, Frank N. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1938 July 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 May 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 June 30; 2p
    - From Boas, 1939 Aug. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 Sep. 11; 2p
    - From Boas, 1939 Oct. 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 Nov. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 Dec. 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 July 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Nov. 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Dec. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 July 26; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec. 8; 1p
  - Trager, Dr. George L. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Sep. 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Oct. 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Jan. 6; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Jan. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 May 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Sep. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Jan. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Jan. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Jan. 20; 1p
  - Training School for Jewish Social Work...Post war problems of the Jews. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1926; 1p
    - Enc. with Karpf, M.J., 1926 Aug. 9
  - Trakatsch, Josef (Box 91)
    - See Juliusburger, O. (open letter), 1933 Oct. 21
    - See Kuhscher, E. (open letter), 1933 Oct. 21
    - See Kuhscher, E. (open letter), 1933 Oct. 31; 1p
    - Found at end of Oct. 1933
  - Trappe, Aug. F. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1905 Dec. 18; 1p
  - Travers, Henry H. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1897 Apr. 23; 1p
  - Trelease, S. F. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1928 Mar. 26; 1p
  - Trelease, William (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1916 May 10
    - To Boas, 1909 Nov. 30
    - To Boas, 1909 Dec. 17
    - To Boas, 1916 May 5
    - To Boas, 1916 May 12
  - Tremols, Jose J. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1930 June 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 May 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 June 7; 1p
  - Tremont Progressive Club (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1933 Nov. 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 20; 1p
  - Trent, M. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1933 Apr. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 24; 1p
  - Trent, W. P. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1915 Dec. 13
    - To Boas, 1917 Feb. 9
  - Trentgraf, Amy (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1898 Mar. 4
  - Triff, M. F. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1931 Oct. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 27; 1p
  - Trombetti, A. (Box 91)
    See also Crombetti, A. (delete)
    - From Boas, 1925 Apr. 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1926 Nov. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1925 Apr. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1925 Apr. 2
  - Trommsdorff, Paul (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 5; 2p
  - Trost, Friedrich (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1925 Mar. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1925 Jan. 25; 2p
  - Trotter, M. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1927 Mar. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 Mar. 5; 1p
  - Trottza Sola, von (Box 91)
    - From Seler, E.G., 1913 July 24
  - Trow Directory and Printing Co. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1905 May 23
    - From Boas, 1905 Dec. 4; 1p
  - Troyanovsky, A. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1936 Dec. 14
    - From Boas, 1936 Dec. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Dec. 21
  - True, F. W. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1898 Mar. 19
    - From Natural Museum Smithsonian Institute, 1891 May 2
  - True, R. H. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1925 Nov. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Nov. 12; 2p
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 26; 1p
    - Enc. A.A.A.S. Committee of one hundred on scientific research. Summary of proceedings at Cleveland, 1930.
  - Truesdell, Leon E. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1936 Nov. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Nov. 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Nov. 14; 1p
    - To Malzberg, Benjamin, 1935 Feb. 15; 1p
  - Tschepourkowsky, E. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1922 Oct.
    - To Boas, 1922 Nov. 15; 2p
  - Tschschenko, Theodore von (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1929 July 12; 1p
  - Tsu, Y. Y. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1921 Feb. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1921 Feb. 18; 1p
  - Tsubin, E. and Korinetz, I. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1927 Apr. 30; 2p
  - Tucker, John F. P. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1940 Aug. 19; 1p
  - Tucker, Marguerite (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1927 Jan. 24; 1p
  - Tufts, J. H. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1929 Dec. 17; 1p
  - Tulpa, Leonid V. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1934 Dec. 24; 2p
  - Tumulty, J. C. (Box 91)
    - From Irvine, B. F., 1917 Nov. 12
  - Tunis, Clyde (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1923 Apr. 18; 1p
  - Turchin, Maia (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1940 Feb. 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 7; 1p
  - Turn-Verein, Cincinnati (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 21; 1p
  - Turnbull, James Beare (Box 91)
    - See Spencer, Louise C., 1940 Feb. 24
  - Turner, J. P. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1932 Dec. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Feb. 13; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Apr. 18; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Sep. 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 Feb. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Feb. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Sep. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Oct. 10; 1p
  - Turner, Lily (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1940 Oct. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 May 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Jan. 27; 1p
    - From Coffin, Henry S., 1941 Mar. 19
    - Enc. with Rautenstrauch, W., 1941 Mar. 21
  - Turner, Lucien M. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1887 Mar. 6
  - Turner, T. W. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1932 Jan. 23; 1p
  - Turner, W. H. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1908 Jan. 2; 6p
  - Tuthill, William Burnet (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1896 Mar. 5
  - Tutner, J. P. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1940 Sep. 11; 1p
  - Tuttle, DR. Jay (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1890 July 25
  - Tyler, F. N. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1919 Sep. 29; 1p
  - Tyler, H. W. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1919 Oct. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 13; 1p
    - Enc. Munro, W.B. and Tyler, H.W. A study of conditions of tenure of college teaching, 1931 Jan. 17
    - See Tyler, H. W., 1931 Feb. 13
  - Tyler, J. M. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1919 Nov. 13; 1p
  - Tylor, Mrs. Anna R. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1896 June 13
  - Tylor, Sir Edward Burnett (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1888 Aug. 15; 2p
    - From Boas, 1888 Aug. 17; 4p
    - From Boas, 1889 Mar. 6
    - From Boas, 1889 Apr. 25; Transcript only?
    - To Boas, 1888 Sep. 11; 4p
    - To Boas, 1889 June 7
    - To Boas, 1889 June 12
    - To Boas, 1889 Oct. 16
    - To Boas, 1889 Dec. 9
    - To Boas, 1889 Dec. 31
    - To Boas, 1890 May 27
    - To Boas, 1890 OOct. 9
    - To Boas, 1891 Aug. 9
    - To Boas, 1894 Dec. 22
    - To Boas, 1895 Apr. 10
    - To Boas, 1895 Apr. 26
    - To Boas, 1895 June 20
    - To Boas, 1895 Aug. 29
    - To Boas, 1895 Sep. 19
    - To Boas, 1895 Oct. 5
    - To Boas, 1896 Jan. 5
    - To Boas, 1896 Sep. 24
    - To Boas, 1896 Nov. 6
    - To Boas, 1896 Nov. 26
    - To Boas, 1897 Feb. 13; 4p
    - To Boas, 1898 Aug. 21; 4p
    - To Boas, 1898 Sep. 2; 4p
    - To Boas, 1898 Oct. 5; 4p
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 8
  - Tyrrell, J. B. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1888 Mar. 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1888 Mar. 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1888 May 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1888 May 4; 1p
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents U
  - Ufer, K. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1930 Nov. 2; 1p
  - Uglow, K. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1911 Mar. 29
  - Uhenbach, Karl (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1923 Apr. 22; 1p
  - Uhl, Byron H. (Box 91)
    - To Fidelity and Deposit Co. of Maryland, 1937 July 9; 1p
    - Enc. with Boas, F. (to Parker, V.L.N.), 1937 July 28
  - Uhl, Edward (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1904 Dec. 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1905 May 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1905 May 27; 1p
  - Uhle, Max (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1903 Nov. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1903 Nov. 12; 2p
    - Found at end of June 1933, 1940 Dec. 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 May 24; 3p
  - Uhlenbeck, C. C. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1915 Oct. 4
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 6
    - From Boas, 1918 Jan. 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1918 Apr. 8; 2p
    - From Boas, 1925 Jan. 31; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 Apr. 9
    - From Boas, 1928 Dec. 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Feb. 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Feb. 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Mar. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1910 May 31
    - To Boas, 1915 Oct. 26
    - To Boas, 1917 Jan. 11
    - To Boas, 1918 Feb. 17
    - To Boas, 1918 Mar. 17; 2p
    - To Boas, 1918 May 18; 2p
    - To Boas, 1918 May 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1918 Aug. 12; 3p
    - To Boas, 1919 Oct. 8
    - To Boas, 1924 Dec. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1925 Jan. 12
    - To Boas, 1925 June 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1926 Feb. 6; 2p
    - To Boas, 1926 Oct. 3; 2p
    - To Boas, 1926 Dec. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 Feb. 28
    - To Boas, 1927 June 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 June 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1928 Nov. 30; 2p
    - To Boas, 1929 Feb. 3; 2p
    - To Boas, 1930 Mar. 28
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 12
    - To Boas, 1932 Jan. 6
    - To Boas, 1932 Jan. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Aug. 16
    - To Boas, 1935 Aug. 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Sep. 15
    - To Boas, 1936 Oct. 4
    - To Boas, 1937 June 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 July 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Aug. 27
  - Uhlenhuth, Dr. E. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 13; 1p
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 May 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 Jan. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 Jan. 31; 2p
    - To Boas, 1923 Jan. 31; 2p
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 17; 2p
  - Uhlson, H. P. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1931 July 10; 1p
  - Uldall, H. J. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1929 May 18; 1p
    - From Boas, 1929 Nov. 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1929 Nov. 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1930 Feb. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1930 Mar. 27; 1p
    - From Boas, 1930 Apr. 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Apr. 5; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 June 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Nov. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Nov. 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Jan. 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Sep. 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Nov. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Nov. 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Dec. 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Jan. 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Oct. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 27; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 May 27; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Aug. 24; 2p
    - From Boas, 1938 Mar. 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 Apr. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1940 Sep. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 May 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 June 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 Aug. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Feb. 12; 2p
    - To Boas, 1930 Mar. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Apr. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 July 21; 2p
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 May 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 June 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 July 25; 2p
    - To Boas, 1932 Sep. 11; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 19; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 June 21; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 3; 3p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 14; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Dec. 21; 2p
    - To Boas, 1934 Dec. 28; 3p
    - To Boas, 1935 Jan. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Mar. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Sep. 3; 3p
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 15; 2p
    - To Boas, 1936 Feb. 20; 2p
    - To Boas, 1937 Aug. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec. 13; 2p
    - To Boas, 1938 Jan. 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1938 Feb. 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Mar. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 July 28; 2p
  - Ulidy, Robert (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 7; 2p
  - Ullman, Ludwig (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 12; 1p
  - Umlauff, Eva (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1931; 2p
  - Umlauff, J. F. G. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1931 May 25; 1p
  - Under the Arctic Circle (Box 91)
    - See Boas, F., 1885 Jan. 18
  - Underhill, Ruth (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1935 Feb. 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Apr. 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 May 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Apr. 28; 1p
    - To Boas
    - Found at end of Dec. 1934, 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 15; 2p
    - To Boas, 1935 May 18; 1p
    - Found a t end of May 1935, 2p
    - To Boas, 1935 June 5; 1p
    - Found at end of Dec. 1935, 3p
    - To Boas, 1936 May 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Sep. 2; 1p
    - Found at end of Dec. 1936, 2p
    - Found at end of Dec. 1936, 3p
  - Underwood Typewriter Co. (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 8; 1p
  - Unger, Abraham (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1941 Sep. 26
  - Union académique internationale (Box 91)
    - From Oslo, 1926 Apr. 26
    - Enc. with Koht, H., 1926 May 2
  - Union Postal Universal (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1912 Mar. 9
  - U.S.S.R. Society of Cultural Relations with Foreign Countries (Box 91)
    See Korinetz, I.
    See Tsubin, E.
  - Union Theological Seminary (Box 91)
    See Rewer, Julius A.
  - United Gas Corporation of Washington (Box 91)
    See Peery, W.K.
  - United German Societies Executive Committee (Box 91)
    - From Koch, E., 1933 Sep. 21
  - U.S. Ambassador in Berlin (Box 91)
    - From Jochelson, W., 1921 Nov. 21; 2p
  - U.S. Bureau of American Ethnology (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1902 Nov. 8
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 29
    - To Boas, 1906 June 29
    - To Boas, 1910 June 28
      - to H.A. Andrews, 1910 June 28
    - To Boas, 1914 May 18
    - To Hunt, G., 1918 Apr. 14; 1p
  - U.S. Bureau of Ethnology (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1887 Sep. 16
    - To Boas, 1890 July 17
    - From Boas, 1900 Oct. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1902 Sep. 25; 1p
  - U.S. Bureau of Immigration (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1933 July 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1932 Oct. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 June 6; 1p
  - U.S. Bureau of Indian Affairs Commissioner (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1907 May 31
    - From Boas, 1933 May 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 May 16; 1p
  - U.S. Bureau of Navigation (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1885 Jan. 16
    - From Boas, 1886 Jan. 2
    - To Boas, 1886 Jan. 2
    - To Boas, 1887 June 3
  - U.S. Census - Director (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 10; 1p
      also see Truesdale, Leon H.
  - U.S. Census Bureau (Box 91)
    See Truesdell, Leon E.
    - also from Boas, 1933 Jan. 10
  - U.S. Civil Service Commission (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1908 Apr. 15
    - From Boas, 1908 Apr. 23
    - From Boas, 1929 Dec. 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1906 June 13
  - U.S. Commissioner of Immigration (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1936 June 6; 1p
      see U.S. Bureau of Immigration
  - U.S. Congress: Act for Preservation of American Antiquities (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1906 June 8
  - U.S. Congress: House (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1916 Jan. 12
    - To Boas, 1938 Mar. 24; 2p
    - Enc. with Celler, E., 1938 Apr. 5
    - Found at end of Dec. 1939
  - U.S. Congress: House Committee on Rules (Box 91)
    - Found at end of Dec. 1939
  - U.S. Congress: House Speaker (Box 91)
    - Found at end of Dec. 1939
  - U.S. Congress: Senate (Box 91)
    - 1937 Feb. 8, 2p
    - Found at end of Feb. 1937, 1937 Feb. 22; 8p
    - from Nat'al Emergency Conference, 1939 June 22
  - U.S. Consul - Berlin (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1936 Feb. 10; 1p
  - U.S. Consul - Bermuda (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1935 Dec. 20; 1p
  - U.S. Consul - Vancouver, B.C., Canada (Box 91)
    - 1938 Sept. 6
  - U.S. Consul Gereral - Berlin (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1936 May 13; 1p
  - U.S. Department of Indian Affairs from Collett (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1933 Sep. 18; 1p
      see carbon copy
    - attached to letter from Gordon, Paul W. to Boas, F., 9/30/33
  - U.S. Department of the Interior (Box 91)
    See also Gordon, Paul W.
    See also Beyer, Silva
    - To Boas, 1903 May 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1907 June 8
  - U.S. Department of the Interior. Secretary (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1907 June 8
    - To Boas, 1903 May 25; 1p
  - U.S. Department of Justice (Box 91)
    - From Avaleare, F.P., 1917 Nov. 1
    - From Kertesz, V., 1917 Nov. 1
    - From Mendelsohn, C. J., 1917 Nov. 1
    - From Mooney, J., 1917 Nov. 1
    - From Swanton, J. R., 1917 Nov. 1
    - From Willman, S.M., 1917 Nov. 1
  - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration, and Naturalization Service (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1937 Oct. 18; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 May 26; 1p
    - From Boas, 1932 Oct 3; 1p
  - U.S. Department of State (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1933 Apr. 5; 1p
    - From Abbot, C.G., 1930 May 16
  - U.S. Department of State. Secretary (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1908 Mar. 25; 2p
    - From Boas, 1911 Aug. 2; 7p
    - From Boas, 1911 Aug. 20
    - From Boas, 1916 Jan. 28
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 28; 2p
  - U.S. Embassy - Berlin (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1898 July 18; 1p
  - U.S. Express Co. (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 17
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 17
    - To Boas, 1910 Jan 31
  - U.S. Government Printing Office (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1936 Oct. 19; 1p
  - U.S. Internal Revenue Act of 1921 (Box 91)
    - Enc. with Boas, F. (to Denny, J.W.), 1923 Oct. 25
  - U.S. Library of Congress (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1920 June 18; 1p
      Open Letter
  - U.S. National Museum (Box 91)
    See also Setzler, Frank M.
    - To Boas, 1894 Jan. 27
    - To Boas, 1895 Nov. 25
  - U.S. Navy Department. Bureau of Navigation Hydrographic Office (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1887 June 3
  - U.S. Navy Department. Washington Navy Yard - Civil Engineers Office (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1887 Sep. 23
  - U.S. Post Office - New York City (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 6
    - From Boas, 1913 Oct. 6
    - To Boas, 1907 Dec. 21
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 3
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 14
    - To Boas, 1915 Jan. 8
    - To Boas, 1914 Jan. 17
    - To Boas, 1914 Feb. 28
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 20
  - U.S. The President, Secretary of State, Congress (Box 91)
    - From Anon, 1938 May 13
  - U.S. State Department (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1915 Apr. 24
  - U.S. Treasury Department (Box 91)
    - See Palmer, Carroll E., 1932 Sep. 30
  - U.S. War Department. Secretary (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1908 Mar. 25
    - From Boas, 1908 Apr.; 2p
  - Universidad Nacional Museo de La Plata (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 18; 1p
  - Universitat Tartu (Dorpat) Estonia (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1935 Sep. 4; 2p
  - University and Bellevue Hospital Medical College, New York University (Box 91)
    See Mandel, John R.
  - University of Chicago (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 21; 1p
    - See Boas, F. (to Princeton Univ. Secretary) See Robertson, D. A. (Graduate Fellowship Comm), 1936 Feb 25; 1p
  - University of Chicago Press (Box 91)
    See Mills, M. G.
  - University of Cincinnati (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 21; 1p
    - see Boas, F. (to Princeton Univ. Sec.)
  - University of Jena, Institute für Mikroscopie (Box 91)
    See Ambronn, Hermann
  - University of Pennsylvania (Box 91)
    - To Boas, 1893
  - University of Santa Clara President (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1921 Dec. 31; 1p
  - University of Sydney Registrar (Box 91)
    - From Boas, 1933 Sep. 25; 1p
      See also Selle, W. A.
  - University of Vienna (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 5; 1p
    - From Boas, 1921 Mar.; 1p
  - University of Vienna, Rector (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1923 Jan. 18; 1p
  - University of Witwatersrand (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1925 Jan. 16; 1p
  - Unknown, 1904-1939; 14 folders (Box 92)
    Folder #9: Sketches of Inuit designs
  - Untermeyer, A. (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 18; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 27; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 28; 1p
  - Untermeyer, Samuel (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1933 May 26; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 June 15
    - To Boas, 1933 May 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 June 12; 1p
  - Unwin, Joseph D. (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1929 Oct. 24; 1p
    - From Stirling, M. W., 1929 July 2
    - Enc. with Unwin, J.D., 1929 Oct. 12
    - To Boas, 1929 Oct. 12; 1p
    - Enc. Stirling, M.W. (to Unwin), 1929 July 2
    - Unwin, Joseph D. (to Stirling), 1929 June 21
    - To Boas, 1929 Nov. 19; 1p
    - To Stirling, M.W., 1929 June 21; 1p
    - Enc. with Unwin, J.D., 1929 Oct. 12
  - Updike, D. M. (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1931 Feb. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 20; 1p
  - Upham, Warren (Box 92)
    - To Boas, 1888 Jan. 9; 2p
  - Upton, N. M. -- (of Mason & Hamlin) (Box 92)
    - To Mrs. M. Boas, 1912 Sep. 24; 2p
  - Urbach, Anna (Box 92)
    - To Heuser, F.W.J., 1923 June 13; 1p
    - To Heuser, F.W.J., 1923 June 18; 1p
    - To Wood, Henry, 1923 Aug. 31; 1p
  - Urbach, Mrs. Anna (Box 92)
    - From Lipkindm, Will, 1939 May 30
    - From Ravené, G., 1897 Jan. 12
    - From Ravené, G., 1897 Apr. 15
  - Urbach, B. J. (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1915 Jan. 15
  - Urbach, Helmut (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1940 Dec. 6; 1p
  - Urban, Henry F. (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 7; 2p
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 9
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 18; 1p
  - Urbiny, Luis G. (Box 92)
    - To Boas, 1913 July 21; 1p
  - Urey, Harold C. (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1940 Dec. 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Aug. 25
    - See Boas, F. (open Letter), 1938 Jan.
    - From Boas, 1938 Apr. 22; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 July 19; 1p
    - See McConnell, F.J., 1939 Jan. 30
    - See McCrea, R.C., 1939 Apr. 22
    - From Boas, 1939 Sep. 30; 1p
      - Open Letter, 1941 Jan. 3; 1p
  - Urgiss, Eva A. (Box 92)
    - To Boas, 1936 Feb. 28; 3p
  - Urtsenius (Box 92)
    - To Boas, 1930 Sep. 27; 2p
  - Urwick, E. J. (Box 92)
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 13; 1p
  - Usher, Abbott Payson (Box 92)
    - To Boas, 1942 May 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 May 9; 1p
  - Utterback, W. I. (Box 92)
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 9; 1p
  - Uzres, John L. (Box 92)
    - To Boas, 1909 May 21
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents V
  - V. C. N. (Box 92)
    - Fragments of Ibycus
    - Found at end of Dec. 1940, 3p
  - Vaeckwith, M. (Box 92)
    - To Boas, 1918 June 1; 2p
  - Vail, C. C. D. (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Mar. 20; 1p
  - Vaillant, George C. (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1932 July 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 July 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 July 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Nov. 17; 1p
    - Found at end of Dec. 1932, 2p
    - Found at end of Dec. 1932, 3p
    - To Boas, 1942 July 20; 1p
  - Valadares, J. (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1934 Oct. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Sep. 20; 1p
  - Valcarcel, Luis E. (Box 92)
    - To Boas, 1941 Feb. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Feb. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Feb. 13; 1p
  - Valle, R. H. (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 1; 1p
  - Van Amringe, J. H. (Box 92)
    - From Boas, 1905 Dec. 13
    - To Boas, 1905 Dec. 14